Guide to the HEARTS & QUARKS Production Materials
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Hearts & Quarks production materials
1987-1988
SC0439
Wagner, Jane.
3.5 Linear feet
Collection consists of original 16mm film negatives (with 3/4 inch video copies), audio tapes, and transcripts of interviews with Dr. Norman Shumway and Prof. Sidney Drell and of a conversation between Shumway and Drell.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Jane Wagner, 1993-1994.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Associated Materials
An overview of the film 'Hearts and Quarks' published 1989 Feb 1 in the Stanford newspaper (Campus Report ) is available in the respositroy.
Jane Wanger
Jane Wagner received her B.Sc and M.Sc in political sociology from the London School of Economics. She completed her master's degree in documentary film production at Stanford University in 1988. Her thesis film, Hearts & Quarks, has been screened at the 20th International Documentary Film Festival in Nyon, Switzerland; the 39th International Film Festival in Berlin; the National Educational Film Festival; and the Montreal International Festival of Women's Films.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
HEARTS & QUARKS, a film about the ethics and application of modern science and technology, was Jane Wagner's masters thesis project for the Dept. of Communications Documentary Film Program at Stanford. It features interviews with physicist Sidney Drell and heart surgeon Norman Shumway.
Description of the Collection
Hearts & Quarks, Two Perspectives on Modern Technology, addresses questions raised by the applications and effects of science in our society; it focuses on the careers of two Stanford University scientists, Sidney Drell and Dr. Norman Shumway. Prof. Drell, a theoretical physicist and arms control expert, is deputy director of the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center; Dr. Shumway, who performed the first U.S. heart transplant in 1968, is chairman of cardiovascular surgery at the Stanford Medical Center. The film combines interviews with historical and contemporary footage.
This collection of production materials includes the l6mm film negatives (with 3/4 inch video copies) of Wagner's interviews with Drell and Shumway and of a conversation between Drell and Shumway; audio tapes of the above as well as class and operating room sounds and the narration; and logs and transcripts.
Access Terms
Drell, Sidney D., (Sidney David), 1926-; Shumway, N. E. (Norman Edward), 1923-2006; Wagner, Jane.; Motion pictures; Phonotapes.; Science--Moral and ethical aspects.; Technology--Moral and ethical aspects.; Videorecordings.
Collection Contents
- Production materials, 1987
  - 16 Neg. Rolls (1-4), UNC 603, undated (Box 1)
  - 16 Neg. Hold Orig., Rolls 5-8, UNC 603, undated (Box 1)
  - 16 Neg. Hold Orig., Rolls 9-12, UNC 603, undated; 6 video reel(s) (Box 1)
  - 16 Neg. Hold Orig., Rolls 13-16, UNC 603, undated; 7 video reel(s) (Box 1)
  - 16 Neg. + 16 I.P., Rolls 16A, 17, 18, 19, 20 Orig., 20 D.N./20I.P., undated; 7 video reel(s) (Box 1)
  - 16 Neg. 16 D.N. 16 I.P. 16 CRoll for titles, Rolls for Title Sequences, UNC 603, undated; 8 video reel(s) (Box 1)
  - H&Q Transcripts, undated (Box 2)
  - H&Q Conversation Drell & Shumway, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - SLAC/Drell Interview Tape #1, undated; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Drell Interview Tape #2, undated; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Operating room amb./ Shumway interview Roll #1, 1987 Feb 25; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sumway interview/Operating room noise/Lab noise Roll #2, 1987 Feb 25; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Amb. Drell's office/Noise at SLAC Roll #3, 1987 Feb 20; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Core 3 & 4/Conversation Drell & Shumway, 1987 Jul 6; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Conversation Drell & Shumway/ Core 1 & 2, 1987 Jul 6; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Shumway/Amb. sound for train birdie & conference, undated; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Drell's class, undated; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Drell/audio interview/ tape #2, 1987 Jul 2; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Shumway/Drell/Audio interview/Tape #1, 1987 Jul 2; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Monitors. Drell & S. Talking Leads, 1988 Apr 27; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Hospital, undated; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Narration, undated; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - H+Q Tape #2, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Shumway, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - H+Q, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Dry run Drell & Shumway, 1987 Jul 24; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - H&Q Tape 1 Interview Drell & Shumway, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Hearts & Quarks 16mm B track neg, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Hearts & Quarks 16mm A&B roll ECN, undated; 2 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)